# TROY BERENTSEN

Staten Island, New York, 10308

Phone: (347) 631-1712 | Email: troyberentsen94@gmail.com LinkedIn:berentsen94 | Github:tmbx9482 | Portfolio: https://tmbx9482.github.io/My-Portfolio-Page/

# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Full Stack Developer with a business, analytical, and technology mindset whose effectiveness at combining creativity and strong impact on delivering results. I've consulted, researched, and managed over 5 years in the digital revolution world and now deep diving into web development in pursuit of a career in software engineering.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5/CSS, JavaScript, C#, C++

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Python

Frameworks: jQuery, React, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Firebase

General: Git/GitHub, Microsoft Office, Google Docs/Slides, SPSS,

### **PROJECTS**

NoteDrop | https://github.com/tmbx9482/Project1\_RUTSchool Project Page | https://tmbx9482.github.io/Project1\_RUTSchool/

- An artist search engine that finds top 10 hit songs and defines lyrics for song choice.
- Deployed two API's servers: Genius & Bandsintown
- I was the project manager and the front end designer/UI expert for the HTML/CSS.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Google Font

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Amazon Transportation Operations Supervisor

December 2018 – Present Staten Island, New York

- Correspond with multiple shipping companies to support daily workflow and business demands.
- Tracking trailers on arrival, departure, and always identifying documentation for driver's destination.
- Maintained 100% accuracy on daily yard audits and zero defects.
- Consolidate data from Excel Spreadsheets, Online Database, Yard Inventory Tools.

### **Inventory Control QA Associate**

### October 2018 – December 2019

- Assisting managers in daily management planning for the department.
- Assigning job duties, coaching, developing, and training associates during prime/peak season.
- Saved production budget by 86% while counting the quantity of products and flagging inaccurate bins.
- Consistency achieving top 10% in meeting daily/monthly productivity and quality goals.

### IT Equipment Coordinator (Seasonal)

November 2018 – January 2019

- Supported the operations team by deploying equipment from the IT inventory to warehouse locations.
- Troubleshoot networking, routing and inter connectivity issues, including network device configuration and low level application interaction.
- Configured IT equipment like: thin client PCs, scanners, printers, and portable handheld terminals.
- Achieved to determine which equipment was RMA, liquidation, and or needed repair devices under warranty or shipping them to manufacture to be troubleshooted.

## **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Flex Bootcamp Certificate:** Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelors Of Science, Business Management: College Of Staten Island, Staten Island, NY Management students gain the skills required to become a business leader in any type of organization or any industry.

Bachelors Of Science, Business Marketing: College Of Staten Island, Staten Island, NY Marketing students gain an effective blend of current theory, academic rigor, and practical applications to enhance personal growth and professionally for careers in promotion and advertising.